Joseph R. Snopek Railroad Collection 2003.0035
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Joseph R. Snopek Railroad Collection
undated, 1902-1999
2003.0035
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
13.0 Linear feet
Author of Diesels to Park Avenue (New England Rails Publishing Company, 1997). Collection consists of photographs, timetables, track guide maps, operator manuals and freight schedules principally of northeastern United States railroads, including the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, Penn Central, Conrail, and Amtrak.
13 linear feet.
Snopek, Joseph. (Collector)
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of timetables, publications, maps, train accident reports, photographic prints and negatives, postcards and ephemera of railroads of New England, particularly the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, better known as the New Haven Railroad, as well as its successor railroads of Penn Central, Conrail and Amtrak.
Series I: Timetables, publications, maps, and ephemera, consists of timetables (employee and public), books, publications, maps, fliers, ephemera, and accident reports of railroads in New England and the northeast United States, particularly those that were functioning in the period between the 1930s and the 1990s. Railroads represented include Amtrak, the Boston & Albany Railroad, the Boston & Maine Railroad, New York Central Railroad, the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, and Penn Central. Also included is literature produced by railfan groups of the northeast United States, including the New Haven Railroad Historical and Technical Association and the Massachusetts Bay Railroad Enthusiasts. Of special interest are locomotive operating and instruction manuals and Interstate Commerce Commission accident reports.
These papers were collected by Mr. Snopek for his personal interest and as research materials in preparation for writing the book Diesels to Park Avenue: The FL-9 Story.
Series II: Photographs, consists of images collected and taken by Mr. Snopek throughout his lifetime, of locomotives, railroad stations and other railroad-related scenes, mostly of railroads in the northeast United States with a few from Canada and the western United States.
Prior to the donation of the collection to Archives & Special Collections the materials, particularly the photographs, were organized and meticulously listed by Robert A. LaMay, Mr. Snopek's co-author on the book Diesels to Park Avenue: The FL-9 Story. The lists Mr. LaMay created are available in each box of photographic prints as aids for access.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the railroads of southern New England, particularly the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Provenance and Acquisition
The collection was donated by Mrs. Virginia Snopek of Granby, Massachusetts, in 2003.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Biography/History
Joseph R. Snopek was born in Holyoke, Massachusetts, in 1943. He graduated from the University of Massachusetts in Amherst and worked for Allied Resources Corporation in East Hartford, Connecticut, as the Director for Technical Services Engineered Safety Systems and Chief Engineer. He was a resident of Granby, Massachusetts, beginning in 1965 and a member of the Civil Air Patron and the National Guard. He died on November 4, 2000, in Holyoke.
Mr. Snopek was a co-author, with Robert A. LaMay, of Diesels to Park Avenue: The FL-9 Story (Granby, MA: New England Rails Pub. Co., 1997). The EMD FL9 (New Haven Class EDER-5) was a dual-power electro-diesel locomotive, capable of diesel-electric operation and of operation as an electric locomotive powered from a third rail. Sixty units were built between October 1956 and November 1960 by General Motors Electro-Motive Division for the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad.
Amtrak.; Conrail.; Locomotives.; Maps.; New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad.; Photographic negatives.; Photographs.; Publications.; Railroads--New England--Photographs.; Reports.; Timetables.
- Series I: Timetables, publications, maps and ephemera, undated, 1907-1999
  - Timetables, books, publications, 1909-1990; 1.3 Linear feet Folders, A-B (Box 1)
    Scope and Content Note
    Subjects include:
    Amtrak: "Amtrak Employee Timetable No. 3" (1978), "Amtrak Passenger Car Operating Instructions" (1984), and Operating Rules and Instructions (1983-1990).
    Association of American Railroads: "Field Manual of the A.A.R. Interchange Rules" (1970).
    Boston and Albany Railroad: Public Timetables: Sept. 29, 1935; Jan. 18, 1938; Jan. 14, 1939; Nov. 12, 1939; Aug. 3, 1947; Apr. 28, 1957; Apr. 28, 1963; Apr. 26, 1964; Employee Timetables (System): No. 162 (1950); Train Register: Springfield, Mass. Railroad Station (October 1-31, 1950) (photocopy); Steam Locomotives Data Booklet, 1929 (substantial number of pages missing)
    Boston and Maine Railroad: Public Timetables (System): Nov. 22, 1926; June 21, 1937; Oct. 28, 1939; June 20, 1947; Sept. 27, 1953; Oct. 28, 1956; Apr. 27, 1958; Oct. 28, 1962; Employee Timetables: No. 40 (Conn. & Pass. Division, June 25, 1917); Connecticut River Division Timetables: No. 51 (Sept. 24, 1922); No. 55 (Sept. 28, 1924); No. 59 (Sept. 26, 1926); No. 61 (Sept. 25, 1927); Fitchburg Division Timetables: No. 28 (Oct. 2, 1911); Fitchburg Division: No. 57A (April 25, 1926); Southern Division: No. 45A (Dec. 22, 1919); Employee Timetables (System): No. 61 (Oct. 30, 1955); No. 62 (April 29, 1956); No. 63 (Oct. 28, 1956); No. 65 (Oct. 27, 1957); No. 1 (Jan. 6, 1963); No. 9 (Jan. 11, 1965); No. 13 (Apr. 24, 1966); No. 14 (Oct. 30, 1966); No. 15 (April 30, 1967); Employee Timetables: No. 18 (Oct. 26, 1969); No. 20 (April 29, 1973); No. 21 (May 18, 1975), with supplements; No. 22 (Jun. 25, 1978), with supplements; No. 1 (April 27, 1980), with operating rules; Symbol Books: No. 8 (Sept. 24, 1922); Freight Train Symbol Book (July, 1980); Rule Books: "Rules and Regulations of the Operating Department" (Effective June 21, 1909), and "Rules for the Government of the Operating Department" (Effective October 29, 1961); Employee Bulletins: 1979-1985; Postwar Equipment Brochures (Passenger, c. 1948); Summary of Equipment (Jan. 1, 1982); "Questions and Answers on Diesel Locomotive Operation" (Jan. 1, 1952); North Station Track and Yard Books: No. 40 (April 28, 1946); No. 41 (June 21, 1946); No. 42 (Sept. 29, 1946)
    Burlington Northern, Inc.: Chicago Region: Special Instructions No. 5 (May 19, 1974).
  - Timetables, publications, maps, 1963-1999; 1.3 Linear feet Folders, CN-CR (Box 2)
    Canadian National Railroad: Employee Timetables (Champlain Area): No. 72 (April 29, 1962); No. 14 (April 25, 1971); No. 19 (October 28, 1973); Operating Manual for Locomotive Engineers (Diesel), 1966
    Canadian Pacific Railroad: System Map (1991); Atlantic Region Timetable No. 28 (April 28, 1963)
    Chicago and North Western Transportation Company: System Map, 1985
    Conrail: System Maps, 1986 (2), and 1993; Employee Timetables (System): No. 6 (Jan. 15, 1998); Employee Timetables (Central Region): No. 1 (Oct. 1, 1976); No. 2 (Oct. 25, 1981); No. 3 (May 10, 1987); Employee Timetables (Metropolitan Region): No. 1 (April 27, 1980); No. 2 (April 25, 1982); Metro-North Timetable No. 2 (Jan. 1, 1983) (2 copies, along with " Metro-North Commuter Railroad Rules of the Transportation Department," Sept. 26, 1982); Employee Timetable No. 1 (Northeastern Region), June 18, 1978; Employee Timetable No. 2 (Southern Region), Dec. 13, 1981 (Along with 1983 revision); Employee Timetables (Western Region): No. 2 (Dec. 13, 1981) (Two Copies); No. 1 (Oct. 27, 1985); No. 2 (April 5, 1987); Employee Timetables (Albany Division): No. 1 (Jan. 15, 1989) (Two Copies); No. 1 (Feb. 24, 1991) (Accompanied by "Station Pages and Division Special Instructions," July 23, 1995); No. 2 (Jan. 1, 1992); No. 3 (Jan. 1, 1993) (Accompanied by Station Pages and Division Special Instructions, July 1, 1996); Station Pages and Division Special Instructions (Albany Division): for Employee Timetable No. 4 (Feb. 1, 1997) (without timetable); for Employee Timetable No. 6 (Jan. 15, 1998) (without timetable); for Employee Timetable No. 7 (Jan. 15, 1999) (without timetable); Station Pages and Division Special Instructions (by Division): Dearborn Division, for Employee Timetable no. 5 (July 1, 1997); Indianapolis Division, for Employee Timetable No. 6 (Jan. 15, 1998); Philadelphia Division, for Employee Timetables No. 6, and No. 7 (Jan. 15, 1998; Jan. 15, 1999); Pittsburgh Division, for Employee Timetables No. 6, and No. 7 (Jan. 15, 1998; Jan. 15, 1999); Detroit District, for Employee Timetable No. 1 (June 1, 1999; Freight Schedules (April 1, 1976); Freight Schedules, Latest Supplement: Jan. 1, 1988; Jan. 1, 1989; Oct. 1, 1989; Nov. 1, 1989; March 1, 1990; Sept. 1, 1993; Track Maps (Boston - West), April 1979; ZTS Maps: Albany Division, November 1988; Allegheney Division, May 1984; Allegheney Division, July 1984.
  - Timetables, maps, publications, 1939-1998; 1.3 Linear feet Folders, C-N (Box 3)
    [Subjects include:
    Conrail: ZTS Maps: Buffalo Division, May 1987; Mohawk-Hudson Division, May 1985; Mohawk-Hudson Division, January 1987; Locomotive Data (Aug. 1984); Briefs of Joint Facility Agreements (Albany Division), July 26, 1991
    Delaware and Hudson Railway Co.: Through Freight Service Guide (July 1983)
    Erie-Lackawanna Railway Company: System Map of the Friendly Service Route (1974); Employee Timetables: New York Division: No. 6 (Oct. 27, 1963) (Two Copies); No. 3 (April 25, 1971) (Two Copies); No. 3 (Oct. 31, 1965)
    Frankfort and Cincinnati Railroad Company: Employee Timetable No. 26 (Nov. 1, 1949)
    Guilford Transportation Industries Rail Division: Employee Timetable No. 1 (System; Oct. 8, 1987); Rules Governing Transportation (System); Employee Safety Rules (July 1, 1985)
    Long Island Rail Road System Map (1989); Employee Timetable No. 2 (May 16, 1983); Supplements to Timetable No. 2
    Lehigh Valley Railroad: Employee Timetable No. 10 (Aug. 10, 1975) (Two Copies)
    Maine Central Railroad: Employee Timetables: No. 35 (June 20, 1947); No. 37 (April 25, 1948); Public Timetable (Oct. 26, 1958)
    Maine Central Railroad Company and Portland Terminal Company: Employee Timetables: No. 1 (May 14, 1978); No. 2 (April 11, 1982); Freight Schedules (Oct. 11, 1983)
    Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority: Transportation Map (Subway - Bus - Rail) (Summer 1976)
    Missouri Pacific Railroad Co.: Employee Timetables: No. 7 (Oct. 31, 1976); No. 18 (Oct. 25, 1981) (Two Copies)
    New England Central Railroad: Employee Timetable No. 4 (Aug. 1, 1998)
    New Jersey Transit: Employee Timetable No. 2 (Hoboken District / Newark District) (Sept. 16, 1984)
    New York Central Railroad: Public Timetables (System): June 25, 1939; Nov. 12, 1939; June 22, 1941; April 28, 1946; April 27, 1947; April 25, 1954; Oct. 28, 1956; Oct. 27, 1957; April 26, 1959; Employee Timetables: No. 10 (Boston & Albany Division, Mohawk & St. Lawrence Division, Syracuse Division, Buffalo Division; Oct. 29, 1961); No. 73 (Electric Division, New York Terminal District; April 27, 1952); No. 75 (Electric Division, New York Terminal District; April 26, 1953); No. 73 (Erie Division; April 26, 1953); Employee Timetables (Harlem Division, Putnam Division): No. 69A (June 18, 1950); No. 71 (April 29, 1951); No. 73 (April 27, 1952) (Two Copies); Employee Timetables (Mohawk Division, Hudson Division); No. 69 (April 30, 1950); No. 71 (April 29, 1951); No. 73 (April 27, 1952); No. 74 (Sept. 28, 1952); No. 75 (April 26, 1953); Employee Timetable No. 70 (River Division; April 29, 1951); Book: "Diagrams and Specifications for Steam on the New York Central System" (Locomotive Data Book; 1946); Publication: "Headlight" Employee Magazine (March 1966)
  - Timetables, publications, fliers, ephemera, 1910-1993; 1.3 Linear feet Folders, N-P (Box 4)
    New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Co.: Public Timetables: Sept. 28, 1946 (The Springfield Line); April 26, 1959; June 8, 1947; April 27, 1958 (Scenic Shoreline Route); Promotional Brochure for The Shore Line Route; Employee Timetables: No. 147 (April 27, 1941); No. 168 (April 24, 1949); No. 16 (April 28, 1963); No. 22 (April 24, 1966); No. 23 (October 30, 1966); No. 24 (April 30, 1967); No. 25 (May 12, 1968); Rules for the Government of the Operating Department (Book; Jan. 1, 1943); Booklet: "Engine Assignment, Radius of Operation Diesel-Electric Engines, Tonnage Ratings, Detouring of Trains Due to Emergency Situations" (Oct. 28, 1956); Booklets: "Description of Passenger Equipment:" July 1, 1930 (Two copies); September 30, 1956 (one copy); Promotional Brochure for the "Comet" (1935; three copies); "Assignment of Work Equipment and Cabooses" (Feb. 1, 1953); "The Electric Lines of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad: Their Operation in Connecticut and Rhode Island" (1975 reprint of 1910 article); Waybill envelopes (undated); "Along the Line" employee magazine (Nov.-Dec. 1946)
    New Haven Railroad Technical Information Association, Inc. (NHRTIA): "General Information About the Association for Prospective Members" (June 30, 1963); Diesel Locomotive Informational Sheets (c. 1970); Publications: "The NHRTIA Bulletin," nos. 30-36 (May 1969 - August 1970); Vol. II (Nos. 1-4; February - November 1971); Vol. III (Nos. 1, 3, and 4; February 1972 - Autumn 1972); Vol. IV (Nos. 1 and 2; Winter 1973 - Spring 1973); Data Sheets: No. 3 (Steam Locomotives; 1971); No. 4 (Diesel Locomotives; 1972); No. 5 (Passenger Cars; 1972); No. 6 (Self-Propelled Passenger Equipment; 1970); No. 7 (Steel Caboose; 1949); No. 8 (Models [Commercial]: Locomotives, Passenger Cars; 1973); No. 9 (Modeler's Color Charts / Decals; 1970); No. 10 (Allyn's Point, Cedar Hill Yards/OCRR System Map; 1970); No. 11 (Box Cars; 1971); No. 12 (Cab Signals, Catenary Bridges; 1971-1972); No. 14 (Photographs / Sources; 1971-1973); No. 15 (Architecture--Stations, Coal Tower, Engine House Data, Signal tower; 1970-1973); No. 16 (Locomotive Roster of 1872, 1893 Description of Equipment, Penn Central Renumbering; 1969-1973); No. 17 (Properties owned and operated in 1917; 1973); No. 18 (Electric Locomotives; 1970-1973)
    Northeast Operating Rules Advisory Committee (NORAC): Operating Rules (Fourth Edition; Jan. 1, 1993)
    Penn Central Railroad: Public Timetable (Boston Area), May 19, 1974; Employee Timetables: Central Region: No. 1 (April 28, 1968); No. 2 (Dec. 1, 1968); Eastern Region: No. 7 (Nov. 14, 1971); No. 8 (April 30, 1972); Lake Region: No. 2 (Dec. 1, 1968); Metropolitan Region: No. 1 (April 26, 1970); No. 4 (July 17, 1972); New Haven Region: No. 26 (Feb. 2, 1969); No. 1 (April 27, 1969); No. 2 (Jan. 18, 1970); No. 3 (April 26, 1970); New York Region: No. 1 (April 28, 1968); No. 2 (Dec. 1, 1968); No. 3 (April 27, 1969); Northeast Corridor Region: No. 11(May 19, 1974); Northeastern Region: No. 3 (June 29, 1969); No. 6 (Oct. 29, 1972); No. 7 (May 19, 1974).
  - Timetables, ephemera, publications, 1907-1983; 0.5 Linear feet Folders, P-U (Box 5)
    Penn Central Railroad: Employee Timetables: Southern Region: No. 2 (Oct. 27, 1968); No. 3 (April 27, 1969); No. 5 (Nov. 14, 1971); Rules for Conducting Transportation (April 28, 1968); Station Rules: Station Employes (July 1, 1968); "Penn Central Post" Employee Magazine (April 1970)
    Pennsylvania Railroad: Supplemental Instructions to Operation, Signal and Interlocking Rules (Sept. 25, 1949)
    Pittsburgh & Lake Erie Railroad Co.: Postcard book: "Road to the Future: The Pittsburgh & Lake Erie Railroad Co." (July 1, 1964)
    Providence and Worcester Railroad Co.: Freight Schedules (Sept. 9, 1983); "The Charter of the Providence and Worcester Railroad Company and the By-Laws" (1907)
    Rutland Railway Corporation: Employee Timetables: No. 122 (April 29, 1951); 123 (Sept. 30, 1951)
    Union Pacific Railroad Company: Employee Timetables: Eastern District: Nebraska Division: Bridge Subdivision: No. 16 (April 24, 1966); No. 22 (Oct. 29, 1967); 25 (June 22, 1969); Employee Timetables (System): No. 5 (May 31, 1981); No. 6 (May 23, 1982); No. 7 (July 17, 1983)
    Duplicate Timetables and Ephemera: New York Central Railroad New England Area Time Table (April 28, 1963) (Four Copies); Boston and Maine Railroad fliers on new passenger coaches (47)
  - Administrative records, prelimary sketches (blueprints), publications, maps, undated, 1919-1995; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 6)
    Subjects include "Railfan" literature:
    Massachusetts Bay Railroad Enthusiasts, Inc.: "Trip Brochure and Route Description: 'New England States Limited' Special Train Operated from Boston to Brattleboro, Vermont" (Feb. 25, 1984); "A Railfan's Guide to Eastern Massachusetts and Rhode Island" (map, Nov. 1986); Publications: "Sam Pottinger's Steel Rails West" series of Rail maps and guides: "The Afton Canyon Rail Map and Guide," "The Cajon Pass Rail Map and Guide," "The Los Angeles and Area Rail Map and Guide," and "The Tehachapi Rail Map and Guide;"
    Boston and Albany Railroad: Accident Account, Chester, Massachusetts, Clipping from "The Springfield Union," August 30, 1943, detailing railroad disaster of August 1893; Accident report from Interstate Commecre Commision, Washington: "Report No. 3655, Boston and Albany Railroad Company, In Re Accident Near Woronoco, Mass., on August 18, 1955;"
    Delaware and Hudson Railroad: Accident Report No. 4125, Ballston Spa, N.Y., August 12, 1967
    Boston & Maine Railroad: Ephemera: Locomotive Naming Contest (no date); Operating Forms, 1938-1952; Train Car List, April 1, 1923
    Central Vermont Railroad: Photograph and data on 700 Class Steam Locomotive (Freight) (no date); Shop Report, May 5, 1952; Operating Forms, 1952
    New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad: Clippings (March 1, 1937), on new locomotive class construction; Shop Report: Readville Shops, May 28th, 1949; April 19, 1949; Southampton Street Engine House: May 27, 1948; June 1, 1950; June 14, 1950; Operating Forms, 1950-1968
    Frisco Lines: Locomotive Blueprint, #4210; Lehigh Valley Railroad: Operating Forms, 1958; New York Central Railroad: Operating Forms, 1942-1968; Penn Central Railroad: Operating Forms, 1969-1970
    United States Railroad Administration: Official Railway Equipment Register (March 1919); Official Railway Equipment Register (Vol. LXXII, No. 4, April 1957)
    Railway Equipment and Publication Co.: "The Official Register of Passenger Train Equipment:" No. 5 (March 1945); No. 18 (Jan. 1953); No. 22 (Jan. 1957); No. 27 (March 1962)
    Trans/Media: "A Trackside Handbook" (1984), with Update No. 3 (1986)
    Kalmbach Books: "The Compendium of American Railroad Radio Frequencies" by Gary L. Sturm and Mark J. Landgraf (1995)
    Alco Diesel Electric (General Electric): Operating Manual, 1600 HP Freight-Passenger Locomotive (1952); Budd: Budd Rail Diesel Car Operator's Manual, 6201 and Up (1955); Fairbanks-Morse: Diesel-Electric Locomotive Enginemen's Manual (1957)
    General Electric: AC440 CW Locomotive Operating Manuals, with Integrated Function Control: For Chicago & Northwestern Road Numbers: 8801-8835 (1994); For Southern Pacific Transportation Company Road Numbers: 100-378 (1995); DASH 9-44CW Diesel-Electric Locomotive Operating Manuals: For Chicago & Northwestern Road Numbers: 8601-8685 (1993); For Hamersley Iron Pty. Limited Road Numbers: 7065-7093 (1994); For BC Rail Road Numbers: 4641-4644; U25B Diesel-Electric Locomotive Blueprints (New York, New Haven and Hartford) (Pre-1970); U25B Locomotive Educational Manual (1963); U25B Renewal Parts Guide
    General Motors, Electro-Motive Division: 5400 Hp Diesel Freight Locomotive Instruction Manual, for Boston & Maine Railroad Nos. 4200 to 4223; DDA40X Locomotive Operator's Manual (1969); GP38-2 Locomotive Operator's Manual (1979); 450PH Locomotive Service Manual (Massachusetts Bay Transporation Authority, November 1978); GP40-2 Locomotive Operator's Manual: Third Edition (April 1975); Fourth Edition (March 1977); GP40X Locomotive Operator's Manual: First Edition (October 1977); GT26CW Locomotive Operator's Manual: Second Edition (April 1974); MP15 Locomotive Operator's Manual: Second Edition (March 1977); SD40-2 Locomotive Operator's Manual: Fourth Edition (August 1975); SD45-2 Locomotive Operator's Manual: Third Edition (November 1973); SW1500 Locomotive Operator's Manual (February 1973); SW1000-SW1500 Locomotive Operator's Manual: Third Edition (November 1969)
    MLW-Worthington Limited: Locomotive Operating Manuals: Century Series Road Locomotives (May 1969);M-Line: M-630 and M-636 Road Locomotives (January 1970); MX 620 and MX 624 Operating Manual (1971)
    Morrisen Knudsen Corporation: FL-9M Locomotive Operator's Manual (July 1993) (Two Copies)
    Pullman Standard: Maintenance Training Guide: For Push-Pull Suburban Service Passenger Cars.
  - Accident reports, 1938-1979; Unfoldered
    Subjects include: Interstate Commerce Commission Railroad Accident Investigation Reports
    - 1938-1961, 0.5 Linear feet (Box 7)
    - 1962-1979, 0.5 Linear feet (Box 8)
- Series II: Photographs, undated, 1902-1991
  - Photographs, undated, 1910, 1922, 1934-1936, 1941, 1943, 1945-1946, 1948, 1957-1958, 1960-1961, 1963-1966, 1967-1969, 1970-1974; 0.25 Linear feet Unfoldered (Box 9)
    Subjects include: Railroad photographs (numbered and described in box list): New Haven Railroad (98), Penn Central (75), Boston & Maine Railroad (57), Erie Lackawanna (28), Canadian Pacific (2), Bangor & Aroostook (2), United Aircraft (4), Green Mountain (1), Pioneer Valley (1).
  - Photographs, ephemera, undated, 1928-1976; 0.25 Linear feet Unfoldered (Box 10)
    Subjects include: Railroad photographs (5x7") (numbered and described in box list): Lehigh Valley (19), Providence & Worcester Railroad (4), Delaware & Hudson (4), Rutland (2), Ashuelot & Connecticut River (1), New York Central Railroad (2), Amtrak (1), Vermont Valley (3), Sullivan County (2), Boston & Albany Railroad(7). Locomotive Manufacturer Specification Cards: Fitchburg Railroad (3), Boston & Albany (5), New York Central (30), Indiana Harbor Belt (1), Maine Central (17), Central New England (3), New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad (18), Central Vermont (9), Boston & Maine (34).
  - Photographs, undated, 1921-1981; 0.25 Linear feet Unfoldered (Box 11)
    Subjects include: Railroad photographs (numbered and described in box list): New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad (54), New York Central Railroad (67), Conrail (10), Bay Colony (1), Pioneer Valley (1), Delaware & Hudson (4), Union Pacific (1).
  - Photographs, undated, 1921-1981; 0.25 Linear feet Unfoldered (Box 12)
    Subjects include: Railroad photographs (numbered and described in box list): Boston & Maine Railroad (52), Soo Line (1), Canadian Pacific (2), Chicago & Northwestern (1), Santa Fe (2), General Motors (1), Combustion Engineering (1), Maine Central (8), Providence & Worcester (11), Lehigh Valley (16), Central Vermont (24), Reading (1), Southern Pacific (2), Erie Lackawanna (1), Canadian National (1), Rutland (2), Penn Central (6), Amtrak (1), Vermont Valley (1), Sullivan County (1), Green Mountain (1), Steam Town Foundation (2), Boston & Albany (7).
  - Photographs, undated, 1931-1971; 0.5 Linear feet Envelopes (Box 13)
    Subjects include Railroad photographs: New Haven Railroad steam and diesel locomotives, multiple unit trains, and cars (passenger and freight). Of Special Interest: Photographs of "The Comet", a stream-lined high-speed train debuted by the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in the 1930s.